Love is in the hair.
There's Something About Mary is a romance, comedy
film directed by Peter Farrelly.
For Ted, prom night went about as bad as it’s possible for any night to go.
Thirteen years later, he finally gets another chance with his old prom date, only to run up
against other suitors including the sleazy detective he hired to find her.
Mary Jensen, played by Cameron Diaz.
Pat Healy, played by Matt Dillon.
Ted Stroehmann, played by Ben Stiller.
Tucker, played by Lee Evans.
Dom Woganowski, played by Chris Elliott.
Magda, played by Lin Shaye.
There's Something About Mary is a 1998 American romantic comedy film directed by the
Farrelly brothers, who co-wrote the screenplay with Ed Decter and John J.
The film features Cameron Diaz as the title character, while Ben Stiller, Matt Dillon, Lee Evans, and
Chris Elliott all play characters who are in love with Mary, and vying for her affection.
There's Something About Mary was released theatrically
on July 15, 1998, by 20th Century Fox.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, who
praised its humor and Diaz's performance.
The film became a major box office success, grossing over $369 million worldwide against its
$23 million budget, becoming the fourth-highest-grossing film of the year.
It is placed 27th in the American Film Institute's 100 Years, 100 Laughs: America's
Funniest Movies, a list of the 100 funniest movies of the 20th century.
In 2000, readers of Total Film magazine voted There's Something
About Mary the fourth-greatest comedy film of all time.
Diaz won a New York Film Critics Circle Award for Best Actress, an MTV Movie Award for Best Performance, an
American Comedy Award for Best Actress, a Blockbuster Entertainment Award for Best Actress.
Her performance additionally was nominated for the Golden Globe Award
for Best Actress – Motion Picture Musical or Comedy.
The film was also nominated for a Golden Globe Award for
Best Motion Picture – Musical or Comedy.
It won four out of eight MTV Movie Awards, including Best Movie.
The film explores themes of surgeon, romcom, stalker, dream girl, taboo.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and thought_provoking.